So, I told you earlier that sometimes you might be the end user of your
إذًا قد أخبرتكم أنكم أحيانًا قد تكونون المستخدم النهائي
own documentation.
لوثائقكم الخاصة.
I'm here with Art, director of engineering here at Udacity.
أنا هنا بصحبة آرت، مدير قطاع الهندسة هنا في Udacity.
So Art, tell me a horror story.
إذًا أخبرني يا آرت عن قصة رعب؛
Tell me a time when you're really kicking yourself for
أخبرني بوقت توبِّخ فيه نفسك
not writing documentation.
لأنك لم تكتب توثيقًا.
>> That's a good question, Walter.
>> هذا سؤال جيد يا والتر،
Feedbacks, early in my career.
وإجابته تكمن في وقت تقديم الملاحظات على عملي، في وقت مبكر من حياتي المهنية.
I was doing a project for
كنت أنفذ مشروعًا
a very sort of conservative stuffy investment bank on Wall Street.
لصالح بنك استثماري من النوع شديد التحفظ والعجرفة في شارع وول ستريت،
And I was doing the support screen that comes up like,
وكنت أنفذ شاشة الدعم التي تظهر لتحاكي موقف
if somebody that's using the app needs help.
ما إذا كان شخصًا يستخدم التطبيق ويحتاج مساعدة.
They click help and it comes up with a phone number.
نقروا على زر help وظهرت الشاشة مصحوبة برقم هاتف محمول،
But we didn't yet have the phone number, so like a placeholder phone number.
لكن لم يكن لدينا رقم لهاتف محمول بعد لذا ظهر رقم هاتف ينوب عنه؛
But I forgot to put in the read me,
لكني نسيتُ إدخال الرقم في وثيقة read me
that somebody needed to update that before they shipped it.
التي احتاج أحدهم إلى تعديلها قبل أن يشحنوها.
So I just put in the first thing that popped into my mind,
لذا أدخلتُ الرقم في أول شيء قفز إلى ذهني،
which was 1-900 of the name of the company, we'll say, ABC-4EVA.
وهو جزء يمثل 1-900 من اسم الشركة؛ لنقُل إنه ABC-4EVA.
>> [LAUGH] >> 4EVA, right?
>> [ضحك] >> اسمه 4EVA أليس كذلك؟
>> Yeah.
>> أجل.
>> And I shipped it, I collect my fee, don't think anything of it.
>> وقمتُ بشحنها وحصلتُ على أجري ولم أفكر بأي شيء من هذا الأمر.
Six months later, I get this frantic call from the project manager.
بعد ستة أشهر جاءتني تلك المكالمة المفعمة بالغضب من مدير المشروع،
Freaking out because one of their customers had called the number,
والذي كان الغضب يسيطر عليه لأن أحد عملاء البنك اتصل بالرقم الظاهر في شاشة الدعم.
nobody ever updated the help number.
لم يكن أحد قد انتبه إلى تحديث رقم المساعدة.
This guy calls me up and he's like,
اتصل بي هذا الشاب وكان يتساءل:
why did you put an adult 900 number on the help screen of our app?
لماذا وضعت رقمًا 900 للبالغين على شاشة المساعدة على تطبيقكم؟
Because I had forgotten to document that it was just a placeholder and
نظرًا لأنني نسيتُ توثيق أن هذا الرقم مجرد نائب عن الرقم المطلوب،
somebody in Utah updated it.
وأن شخصًا ما في مدينة أوتاه قد حدَّثه.
[CROSSTALK] [LAUGH] >> No, God.
[كلام متداخل] [ضحك] >> لا، يا إلهي.
[LAUGH] >> [LAUGH] That's not even a true story.
[ضحك] >> [ضحك] هذه ليست قصة حقيقية من الأساس،
[LAUGH] You'd never do something like that, right?
[ضحك] لا يمكن أن تفعل شيئًا كهذا، أليس كذلك؟
>> I know, I know.
>> أعلم، أعلم.
Yeah, I would never.
نعم لم أكن لأفعل شيئًا كهذا.
>> What is-
>> ما هذا
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
>> I'm future Walter, and
>> أنا والتر القادم من المستقبل،
I completely agree with everything you just said, Art.
وأتفق تمامًا مع كل ما قلته لتوّك يا آرت.
Present Walter over here forgot to document the code on some
لقد نسي والتر الموجود هنا والذي يعيش في الحاضر أن يوثِّق الرمز
of the projects we've been working on.
على بعض المشاريع التي نعمل بها حاليًا،
And now, we can't seem to remember what we were thinking.
والآن لا يمكننا التظاهر بأننا نتذكر ما كنّا نفكر به.
>> Walter, I'm so disappointed.
>> والتر، أنا محبط جدًا.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
>> Take a look at some of your own older projects.
>> ألقِ نظرة على بعض مشروعاتك الأقدم؛
Can you remember everything that you were thinking when you were writing
هل يمكنك أن تتذكر أي شيء كنت تفكر به عندما كنت تكتب
that code.
ذلك الرمز؟
Wouldn't it be helpful to have a handy reference of all the decisions that
ألم يكن مفيدًا لك أن تمتلك مرجعًا في متناول يديك لكل القرارات
past you made.
التي اتخذتها في وقت سابق؟